Irvin Poley Knipe Papers
Irvin Poley Knipe Papers
1858-1932
Knipe, Irvin Poley.
1 linear ft.
Correspondence of the Pennsylvania attorney.
2741996
Biographical History
Irvin Knipe was an attorney and Republican Party official in Norristown, Pennsylvania. He was born 22 Feb 1866 in Norristown, Montgomery, Pa, died 20 Jan 1930 in Norristown, Montgomery, Pa; married to (1) Margaret R. Richardson 23 Feb 1899 and (2) Anna Elizabeth Lovett. He was a partner in the law firm of Wanger and Knipe with Irving P. Wanger who served from 1893 to 1911 in the United States House of Representatives.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Irvin Poley Knipe Papers consists of correspondence and a small amount of miscellanea.
Correspondence contains general correspondence from the law firm of Wanger and Knipe as well as family correspondence.
Miscellaneous consists of a log of expenses of the estate of Edward Hough Trotter and some loose pages from a book on printing.
Arrangement of the Collection
General correspondence is arranged chronologically with the bulk being from the years 1907, 1920 and 1922.
Family correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
Miscellaneous is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Knipe, Irvin Poley.; Wanger, Irving Price, 1852-1940.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Lawyers -- Pennsylvania.; Norristown (Pa.); Montgomery County (Pa.); Correspondence.; Estate records.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1967.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - General, 1858; 1863 (Box 1)
  - General, 1870-1879 (Box 1)
  - General, 1906 (Box 1)
  - General, 1907; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1908-1910 (Box 1)
  - General, 1917-1919 (Box 1)
  - General, 1920; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - General, 1921 (Box 2)
  - General, 1922; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - General, 1929-1932 (Box 2)
  - General, undated (Box 2)
  - Family correspondence
    - Knipe, George, 1922 (Box 2)
    - Knipe, Jay C., 1920 (Box 2)
    - Knipe, Norman L., 1920 (Box 2)
    - Knipe, R. Laura, 1911; 1920 (Box 2)
    - Ogden, Emily P., 1920 (Box 2)
    - Ogden, Winston K., 1920-1922 (Box 2)
    - Poley, Helen, 1922 (Box 2)
    - Poley, Horace S., 1922 (Box 2)
    - Poley, Warren H., 1921-1922 (Box 2)
    - Ralston, Emily R., 1922 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Expenditures of the estate of William Hough Trotter, 1872-1896 (Box 2)
  - Loose pages from a book on printing, undated (Box 2)